emeraldinsight.com 2019-12-24

# Policies and Information | Emerald Insight

This notice explains how information about you is used. Emerald Publishing Limited ( **Emerald** ) is committed to protecting your personal information.

In this notice, references to ‘we’ or ‘us’ means Emerald and our group companies from time to time. More information about our group companies can be found on the Emerald Group website. References to ‘you’ means anyone using our websites, products or services whose personal data, contact details or other information is provided to us.

Information that we gather about you may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, IP address and any other unique means of identification or bespoke data shared with us (including but not limited to organization, role, affiliations, department, education and skills, sector or industry, financial and pay details, geographic location, social media accounts, preferences or purchase history) and your online behaviours and interactions with our websites or products.

We may also obtain information about you from third parties, such as your employer, our group companies, service providers and agents.

We gather information directly from you and also via our websites and other technical systems. These may include, for example, our:

  * computer networks and connections
  * communications systems
  * authentication methods, including single sign on and username/password credentials
  * tracking technologies (such as click through links, cookies and web beacons)
  * email and instant messaging systems
  * intranet and internet facilities
  * telephones, voicemail, mobile phone records
  * other hardware and software owned, used or provided by or on behalf of us and our group companies.

When you use our website we may gather information about you through Internet access logs, cookies and other technical means.

‘Cookies’ are text files placed on your computer to collect internet log information and user behaviour information. These are used to track website usage, monitor website activity and for other data processing reasons set out below. A cookie does not contain information that allows us to identify an individual user.

Some of the cookies we use are essential for parts of the site to operate and have already been set. You may delete and block all cookies from this site, but parts of the site will not work.

To find out more about the cookies we use and how to delete them you can visit the help page for your specific browser as below:

You can [read more detail on our use of cookies here](http://www.emeraldgrouppublishing.com/about/policies/cookiepolicy.htm).

If you need any further detail, please contact [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com)

We may process your personal data for our legitimate business purposes (or those of our group companies), such as:

  * delivery of services
  * to enhance, modify, personalize or otherwise improve our services for the benefit of our customers including reporting on usage trends
  * to enhance the security of our network and information systems
  * to better understand how people interact with our websites or products
  * improving the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising
  * to comply with legal or regulatory obligations and good practice
  * to contact existing customers or individuals that have shown an interest in our products or services.
  * We always carefully consider your interests and your personal data rights before doing this. If you have any concerns about us processing your personal data for these reasons, you have the right to object. If you wish to do so, please contact [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com).

In other circumstances, such as for marketing activities, we will only process personal data where you have provided your consent for us to do so. You can withdraw this consent at any time and if you wish to do so please contact us at [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com), or, if you are have a profile with us, by visiting your personal profile page.

Emerald will only keep data for as long as is reasonable, based on the nature of the data and the reason for processing. If you would like more detail about our retention policies that are applicable to your personal data, please contact [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com).

We may disclose and exchange information with our group companies, service providers, representatives and agents, as well as with law enforcement agencies and regulatory bodies for the above reasons.

Information may be held at our offices and those of our group companies, service providers, representatives and agents as described above. Information may be transferred to other countries around the world, including those without data protection laws equivalent to those in the UK, where required for our processing activities. We have security measures in place to seek to ensure that there are adequate safeguards in place to protect the data we hold.

If you are an author, when you submit your article or book manuscript to Emerald, your name, email address, affiliation and other contact details will be used for dissemination of your published article or book and for delivery of Emerald Publishing services. This involves sharing data with third party partners involved in the production and publication process. By way of example, this includes editors and reviewers. We may use third party providers to verify personal and other information you have provided to us in connection with any manuscript you submit to us for publication. 

It is usual for your name and contact details to be included in the published content. Your published article or book will be made available on our website, and, for maximum discoverability, will be distributed to a number of third parties including abstracting and indexing service providers, content repositories, content aggregators and library discovery tools. We may also share your contact details with third party providers of author services to allow you to make use of their services. 

As an author, you must ensure that all co-authors and all significant contributors consent to publication of the article or book and to being named as a co-author or contributor to the article or book. If you are a co-author or significant contributor, we will process your personal information on the basis that the author has obtained your consent for us to do so. 

If you are a reviewer, your name will appear as a reviewer in the published journal you reviewed. If you object to your name being published, please contact [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com). 

Please contact [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com) if:

  * you would like to correct or request information that we hold relating to you;
  * to object to our processing of your personal data;
  * to update your consents (if you have a profile, you can update your consents by visiting your personal profile page).

When making your choices, please bear in mind that they may affect your use and enjoyment of our services and products.

If you have any concerns about the way that we process your personal data please contact us. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

We do not knowingly collect personal data relating to children under the age of 16. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 16 and think that we may have information relating to that child, please contact us at [support@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:support@emeraldinsight.com).

We will ask you to prove your relationship to the child, but if you do so you may (subject to applicable law) request access to and deletion of that child’s personal data.

Changes may be necessary to this notice to reflect legal or data processing developments.

Any significantly different use of your data will be communicated to you. As explained above, you can amend your consents or raise an objection to our processing of data at any time.

### Questions, comments and complaints

If you have any questions, comments or complaints regarding this notice, please contact our customer support team at: 

Emerald Publishing Limited,  
Howard House  
Wagon Lane  
Bingley  
BD16 1WA  
West Yorkshire  
United Kingdom 

Tel: +44 (0) 1274 777700  
Fax: +44 (0) 1274 785200 

E-mail: support@emeraldinsight.com 

### About Emerald Publishing

Emerald Publishing was founded in 1967 to champion new ideas that would advance the research and practice of business and management. Today, we continue to nurture fresh thinking in applied fields where we feel we can make a real difference, now also including health and social care, education and engineering.

Emerald manages a portfolio of nearly 300 journals, more than 2,500 books and over 1,500 teaching cases. Emerald Publishing is part of Emerald Group.

### Improving the Emerald customer offering

Improving the experience for all customers globally is a priority for Emerald. As a result we have provided a new web platform, improved rankings and plan for increases in yearly article growth and these are just the start of a journey we have undertaken to enhance the customer experience with Emerald.

### Supporting education and research

Emerald is a member of the Globally Responsible Leadership Initiative (GRLI), and actively supports research and education worldwide with a number of awards and research grants. View a list of awards.

### Partnerships and collaborations

Emerald works in close collaboration with a number of academic and corporate organizations and associations worldwide, including: the Association to Advance Collegiate Schools of Business (AACSB), the Academy of Management, the International Federation of Library Associations (IFLA), the American Library Association (ALA), the European Foundation for Management Development (EFMD), CEEMAN (Central and East European Management Development Association), amongst others.

Emerald Publishing Limited, registered in England with company number 03080506 and registered office Howard House, Wagon Lane, Bingley, West Yorkshire, BD16 1WA

  1. ### Definitions

In this Licence, the following terms shall have the meanings set out below:

“You” means either an individual subscriber or a student, faculty member, alumnus or employee of an institution, corporate or government subscriber, or a non-subscriber accessing free content.

“Publisher’s Content” means the whole or any part of a copyright-protected literary work, of a database or of any other information product owned or controlled by the Publisher or its suppliers, and includes (without limitation) any illustration, table, figure, header information, abstracts, bibliographic information or any video or computer-animated design embedded or incorporated in such literary work, database or information product. For avoidance of doubt, Publishers’ Content includes manuscripts of books, published journal articles, abstracts and bibliographic information contained in the institutional or subject repositories, where the Publisher has not expressly agreed to the text and data mining of any such content.

“Text and Data Mining” or “TDM” means to perform extensive automated searches of Publisher’s Content, the sorting, parsing, addition or removal of linguistic structures, and the selection and inclusion of content into an index or database for purposes of classification or recognition of relations and associations.

“Text and Data Mining Output” or “TDM Output” means the result of any Text and Data Mining activity or operation, capable of fixation, reproduction and/or communication in any form, such as the creation of an index, reference, abstract, relative or absolute description or representation of Publisher’s Content, an algorithm, formula, metrics, method, standard or taxonomy describing or based on Publisher’s Content, a relational expression or measurement, whether scalable or not, of Publisher’s Content, extraction, alternative representation or translation, expression or discussion of any extracts from mined Publisher’s Content, whether in the form of a direct extraction or a representation in any form which is based on Publisher’s Content.

  2. ### Description and term of text and data mining activities

    1. Upon the terms of this Licence, the Publisher grants you the non-exclusive, non-transferable right to TDM the Publisher’s Content. For the avoidance of doubt, TDM rights are granted here purely for internal non-commercial research purposes.
    2. You may access and use the Publisher’s Content for TDM for so long as you contemporaneously maintain a subscription to such Publisher’s Content (unless you are a non-subscriber accessing only free content).
    3. You acknowledge that all right, title and interest in and to the Publisher’s Content remains with the Publisher and that unauthorized use and/or redistribution of the Publisher’s Content or the TDM Output could materially harm the Publisher.
    4. You may load and technically format the XML version of the Publisher’s Content on your server, PC or laptop to enable access to and use of such Publisher’s Content for TDM purposes by using automated programs or devices to continuously and automatically: (i) download, extract and index information from the Publisher’s Content for the purpose of enhanced navigation of the emeraldinsight.com website to which you separately subscribe; (ii) extract semantic entities from the Publisher’s Content for the purpose of recognition and classification of the relations between them and mount, load and integrate the results on a server used for your text-mining system (i.e. not in libraries, repositories or archives); (iii) derive patterns within the Publisher’s Content; and (iv) evaluate and interpret the TDM Output for access and use by you.
    5. Publisher excludes any warranty regarding the quality of the data, formatting and errors or omissions. The Publisher’s Content is made available “as is” and without warranty of fitness for purpose, satisfactory quality, reliability or completeness and the Publisher disclaims any implied quality in relation to it.
    6. Except as expressly stated in this Licence or otherwise permitted in writing by Publisher, you may not: 
      1. perform systematic or substantive extracting, especially when performed for the purposes to create a product or service for use by third parties;
      2. utilise the TDM Output to enhance institutional or subject repositories in a way that would compete with the value of the final peer-review journal articles, or have the potential to substitute and/or replicate any other existing Publisher product, service and/or solution;
      3. make the results of any TDM Output available on an externally facing server or website;
      4. allow a third party to harvest any TDM Output to an internal server;
      5. extract, develop or use the Publisher’s Content in any commercial activity;
      6. abridge, modify, translate or create any derivative work based on the Publisher’s Content, except to the extent necessary to make it perceptible on a computer screen;
      7. remove, obscure or modify in any way any copyright notices, other notices or disclaimers as they appear in the Publisher’s Content; and/or
      8. substantially or systematically reproduce, retain or redistribute the Publisher’s Content.
  3. ### Breach

    1. In addition to any contractual rights and remedies under the applicable law, the Publisher shall retain the right to deny access to any Publisher-hosted content where you are in breach of any of the conditions of this Licence. Where you have made available any of the Publisher’s Content or any resulting TDM Output available to third parties, Publisher shall be entitled to terminate this Licence and also to charge you any subscription fee that would have been payable to the Publisher, had the use in question been agreed. For avoidance of doubt, the foregoing contractual remedies apply in addition to and not in substitution of any rights and remedies for breach available in law, such as the right to claim damages and disgorging of any profits generated by reason of any TDM Output in contravention of this Licence.
  4. ### Deletion of locally loaded publisher's content

    1. Upon termination or expiry of this Licence, howsoever arising, you shall destroy any copies of Publisher’s Content where this has been locally loaded for purposes of TDM. Where requested by the Publisher, you may be asked to provide a signed certificate of destruction no later than 30 days after termination or expiry.
    2. For the avoidance of doubt, Clause 2.6 of this of this Licence shall remain effective and survive termination of this Licence.

### Emerald text and data mining policy

Emerald believes that a right to read is a right to mine, and supports researchers’ rights to be able to text and data mine content that they have legal access to. 

Authorised users at subscribing institutions have our permission to mine journal content they have legal access to for non-commercial purposes, subject to the terms of our subscription agreements. The outputs of any TDM activities should bear the appropriate attribution of the original Emerald content where possible. 

To allow Emerald to manage server capacity, we would ask that you notify us before conducting any TDM activities on [www.emerald.com/insight](https://www.emerald.com/insight). This will allow us to enable you to complete your activity without technical obstacles and to maintain access for all Emerald users. 

If you have any questions about this policy, or wish to notify us of your planned TDM activity, please contact us at [permissions@emeraldinsight.com](mailto:permissions@emeraldinsight.com)

### Cookie information

#### Some of the features on the Emerald websites require the use of "cookies".

Cookies enhance your experience using our website and help to personalise the service you receive.

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognise a user’s device. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improve the user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests. The cookies used on this website have been categorised based on the categories found in the ICC UK Cookie guide. A list of all the cookies used on this website by category is set out below.

Cookies may be stored by the browser for a single session or for a longer period of time:

  * **Session cookies** are deleted every time the browser is closed down.
  * **Persistent cookies** are not deleted but will be stored for a set duration. Your browser will provide tools to manage cookies, including the option to delete persistent cookies.

### Cookie name

### Purpose

### Type

### Origin

### __Strictly necessary cookies

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website.

Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided.

laravel_session

Used to maintain login throughout a single session. There may be other tokenised cookies associated with this session management function.

Session

Emerald

XSRF-TOKEN

Security token to prevent cross-site request forgery.

Session

Emerald

__cfduid

Used to provide additional security for the web server.

Persistent

Emerald

PHPSESSID

Used to maintain login throughout a single session, also to toggle occasional site settings e.g. language, text-only (visually impaired) or full graphical view.

Session

Emerald

### __Performance cookies

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

**By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**

_hjid

This cookie is set when the customer first lands on a page with the Hotjar script. It is used to persist the random user ID, unique to that site on the browser. This ensures that behaviour in subsequent visits to the same site will be attributed to the same user ID

Persistent

HotJar

_mp

Used to evaluate the Mixpanel analytics service. Mixpanel is used to track user activity on the Emerald site only and subsequent analysis enables us to improve content and service delivery.

Persistent

Mixpanel

_ga 

_gat_ 

_gid 

_utma 

_utmb 

_utmc 

_utmz 

Google Analytics cookies. These track number and duration of visits to the Emerald website as well as details and keywords of searches that led the user to the site. Google Analytics cookies do not identify individual users and every website using Google Analytics deploys a different set of cookies - visitors are not tracked across multiple sites.

Persistent 

Session 

Persistent 

Persistent 

Persistent 

Session 

Persistent 

Google

QSI_HistorySession

Used to enable tester feedback to be captured using forms provided by Qualtrics

Session

Qualtrics

### __Functionality cookies

These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features.They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as marked lists. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

**By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.**

ACTIVE_TAB

Used to maintain the state of a page if the user navigates away, for example to log in, then returns to the original page.

Session

Emerald

searchhistory

Emerald search history cookie. Holds the user's last 10 searches for use in the search history display. Used by EmeraldInsight.

Session

Emerald

markedlist

Emerald session marked list cookie. Holds the content items (up to 10) of a user's session marked list. Used by EmeraldInsight.

Session

Emerald

### __Targeting cookies

These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are placed on our website by our chosen advertising, marketing and analytics providers, social media platforms and search engines with our permission. These cookies remember that you have visited our website and this information is shared with our chosen providers. They collect information about your browsing activities on our website and allow our providers to track you when you visit other websites, platforms or search engines, so that they can serve our adverts to you. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation.

**The partner organisations that supply these additional services provide a mechanism for you to opt out of any tracking and personalisation. Details of how to do this are given below.**

_stid  
_unam  
_uset  

The Emerald website allows users to post links to Emerald content on their social networking profiles via the ShareThis service. ShareThis cookies record which sites and pages have been "shared" and advertisements that users see on subsequent sites may reflect this. On clicking the ShareThis icon, users can opt out of any tracking by ShareThis (a further cookie, st_optout, records this). See the ShareThis privacy policy for more information.

Persistent

ShareThis

_drt_  
id

A number of information pages on the Emerald website display advertisements and these are selected based on the page they appear on and the user's browsing history as recorded by the DoubleClick cookies. On clicking the AdChoices link on each advertisement, users can opt out of any tracking by DoubleClick (both cookies are set to OPT_OUT). See the Google privacy policy for more information.

Persistent

DoubleClick

### Managing/Blocking cookies

You can manage cookies from this site, including blocking or deleting them, by changing the settings in the browser you use, e.g. Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, etc.

Find out how you can do this by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)
